sordum.org 2018-11-10

# Privacy Policy

Below is information regarding Sordum.org’s commitment to protect the privacy of users and to ensure the integrity of the Internet.

(This Privacy Policy was last revised on May 24, 2018)

Internet user privacy is of paramount importance to Sordum.org . The success of our business depends upon our ability to maintain the trust of our users. If for any reason you have concerns about our software or website’s privacy policies, please contact us. We are committed to ensuring that every user’s needs are addressed. Our website address is:  [Sordum.org](https://www.sordum.org/) ,

**Collection of Personal Information**

In the course of delivering this site to you, Sordum.org does NOT collect any personally-identifiable information about you, such as your name, address, phone number or email address without your knowledge, and are taking measures to protect your privacy. You can send email requesting help and your email will NOT be shared in any way with any third party, and will only be used to send replies to you.

You can leave comments on the site and may do so completely anonymously. You may use your “real” email address or name; if you do, that data is associated with the comment. We won’t use the information associated with comments in any way, won’t sell the information or share it with third-parties. We don’t associate IP addresses with comments or store them.

You may sign up to our site newsletter. We use a double opt-in for that and will store your email address for the sole purpose of delivering the newsletter to that email address. You may unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time. Your email address will be removed when you unsubscribe and no record of the data will be kept.

The site displays share and subscribe options for select social networks. These are implemented in the most privacy-friendly manner; they are static links that don’t connect to third-party sites automatically and won’t record any user interaction unless activated by the user.

Ads used on this website can use cookies and/or web beacons to collect data in the ad serving process. You can remove cookies at any time using your browser tools. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this matter, please feel free to [contact us](https://www.sordum.org/contact-us/).

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content from the video hosting site YouTube. We use YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode for the embeds which ensure that YouTube does not collect any visitor data when the page is loaded.

**Analytics**

We do use Google Analytics to collect information about website visits. We have configured Google Analytics to use the lowest period of time for which data that is collected is associated with cookies and user identifiers, and the time period does not reset on new activity.  

**What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us.

You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. Note that we need to be able to link data to you, for instance, by your email address.

**Where we send your data**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/) . After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment, your selected name and email address if filled out, are retained indefinitely on the site.If you subscribe to our email newsletter, we keep your email address in our database until you unsubscribe from the newsletter (which you may do at any time).

**Cookies**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**Third Party Advertising:**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website.

These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).

**Contact information**

Please use our [contact page](https://www.sordum.org/contact-us/) to get in touch with us – Sordum.org.
